<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Mercenary Veteran</name>
		<description>Mercenary Veteran Background</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1" revised="2017/06/07">
			<file name="background-mercenaryveteran.index" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swdriessen/dndbuilder/master/elements/supplements/sword-coast-adventurers-guide/backgrounds/background-mercenaryveteran.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>



  <element name="Mercenary Veteran" type="Background" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_BACKGROUND_SCAG_MERCENARY_VETERAN">
    <description>
      <p>As a sell-sword who fought battles for coin, you're well acquainted with risking life and limb for a chance at a share of treasure. Now, you look forward to fighting foes and reaping even greater rewards as an adventurer. Your experience makes you familiar with the ins and outs of mercenary life, and you likely have harrowing stories of events on the battlefield. You might have served with a large outfit such as the Zhentarim or the soldiers of Mintarn, or a smaller band of sell-swords, maybe even more than one. (See the "Mercenaries of the North" sidebar for a collection of possibilities.)</p>
      <p class="indent">Now you're looking for something else, perhaps greater reward for the risks you take, or the freedom to choose your own activities. For whatever reason, you're leaving behind the life of a soldier for hire, but your skills are undeniably suited for battle, so now you fight on in a different way.</p>
      
    </description>

    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set (Mercenary Veteran)" supports="Gaming Set" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_LAND" />
      <!--<grant type="Background Feature" name="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MERCENARY_LIFE"  />-->


      <select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
        <item id="1">I’m always polite and respectful.</item>
        <item id="2">I’m haunted by memories of war. I can’t get the images of violence out of my mind.</item>
        <item id="3">I’ve lost too many friends, and I’m slow to make new ones.</item>
        <item id="4">I’m full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my military experience relevant to almost every combat situation</item>
        <item id="5">I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.</item>
        <item id="6">I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.</item>
        <item id="7">I have a crude sense of humor.</item>
        <item id="8">I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Ideal" type="List">
        <item id="1">Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Good)</item>
        <item id="2">Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="3">Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Live and Let Live. Ideals aren’t worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Bond" type="List">
        <item id="1">I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.</item>
        <item id="2">Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.</item>
        <item id="3">My honor is my life.</item>
        <item id="4">I’ll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.</item>
        <item id="5">Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.</item>
        <item id="6">I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.</item>
      </select>
      <select name="Flaw" type="List">
        <item id="1">The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.</item>
        <item id="2">I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.</item>
        <item id="3">I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives— and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.</item>
        <item id="4">My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.</item>
        <item id="5">I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.</item>
        <item id="6">I’d rather eat my armor than admit when I’m wrong.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>


</elements>